ALAN AVERY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Location: Chicago, IL **Phone:** 260-580-2216

Email: AlanRAvery@gmail.com

Portfolio: alanravery.com

GitHub: github.com/delayedaa

Enthusiastic programmer with a background in graphic design and more than 10 years of leadership experience. Now excited to merge a well-honed sense of design with an affinity for organized, technical thinking, and produce inspired software that perfectly balances form and function.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, PHP

Libraries and Frameworks: React, AngularJS, jQuery, Node.js, Express, Ruby on Rails, Sass

Database Technology: SQL, PostgreSQL, Mongo

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Github, command-line interface, Google Docs

Programming Competencies: computer science fundamentals, algorithms, information architecture, mobile-centric responsive design, agile development, MVC pattern, APIs, code organization and readability, version control, automated testing, error handling

Web Design: Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY CHICAGO, IL

Software Engineering Immersive Student, 10/2020-01/2021

Completed a 12-week, 500-hour full stack program, providing experience with current front and back end
programming languages, tools, and methodologies, including web architecture, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API's,
Node.js, Express, databases, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Python, and Ruby.

Projects

- A digital version of the game "Guess Who?", in which users play against the computer, asking it questions in an attempt to guess its "Mystery Person". Built using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- A trip-planning web app that allows users to quickly throw an itinerary together, rearrange it with ease, then save it to a database for future use. Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, and PostgreSQL.
- A personal finance web app focused on giving users the ability to create and compare budgets, as well as compare living costs across the United States. Built with a team of fellow students, using React, Sass, Express, and Mongo.

WORK HISTORY

GREAT WOLF RESORTS CHICAGO, IL

Creative Services Manager, 05/2018-06/2020

- Overhauled the internal creative team, following a corporate relocation to Chicago. Related tasks included hiring new talent, acquiring reputable vendors, and establishing processes for successful project management.
- Guided designers, project managers, and freelance creatives in developing marketing and operational materials for each of the company's 19 resorts.

AISLE ROCKET STUDIOS CHICAGO, IL

Associate Creative Director, 11/2017-03/2018

- Supervised a team of art directors and copywriters spread across 3 cities, boosting interoffice verbal communication and problem solving.
- Revived appliance brand Jenn-Air with a suite of updated customer communications, all of which were recreated to improve the customer experience and align with current brand guidelines.

CONVERSANT CHICAGO. IL

Lead Senior Art Director, 08/2017-10/2017

- Established new brand guidelines for parent company Epsilon that revamped its identity and ensured visual consistency with Conversant.
- Mentored a team of local and remote art directors, simultaneously implementing Workfront, a newly-adopted project management tool.

JACK IN THE BOX SAN DIEGO, CA

Creative Services Manager, 05/2014-06/2017

• Oversaw all work produced by the internal creative team, ensuring it met brand standards and arrived on-schedule to over 2,000 restaurants.

AECOM SAN DIEGO. CA

Graphic Designer, 06/2011-05/2014

• Provided comprehensive design services to AECOM's entire Southern California region, prioritizing efficiency and attention to detail.

UPSHOT CHICAGO, IL

Art Director, 04/2007-04/2011

• Generated artwork, from concept to execution, for over 20 national marketing campaigns, including many for Kraft Foods and MillerCoors.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY CHICAGO, IL

Software Engineering Intensive, 2021

THE ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF ART CHICAGO, IL

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Visual Communication, 2006